GIOVANNI BRUNETTI

Big Data and Software Engineer

giovannibrunetti.it gb1609@outlook.com

Cosenza, Italy in linkedin

SUMMARY -

I'm a computer scientist based in Italy focused on working in the Big Data context. I love writing code and solving problems with it!

I have been a Big Data Engineer since 2020 across multiple domains: **energy**, **telecommunications** and **insurance**.

SKILLS -

Technicals: GCP (BigQuery, Composer, DataFlow, BigTable,

ecc), Cloudera Ecosystem, Scala, SQL, Python, Scala, Bash, Docker, Kubernetes, Spark, Hadoop, Hive, Jenkins, Airflow, Kafka, Sonar-Qube, Git, Maven, Sbt, Functional Programming, HDFS, Team Tools and methodologies

(Jira, Confluence, Scrum)

Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Proactive, Team Working,

Passion, Time Management, Challenge Seeker

EXPERIENCE -

10/2022 - NOW

Big Data and Software Engineer

Agile Lab

- Consultant for a major Italian insurance company:
- Data modelling and data partitioning in a Cloudera Platform ecosystem.
 - Defining and developing Spark job using Scala for Ingestion and processing real-time and batch data.
 - Development of NiFi pipeline to orchestrate jobs.
 MAIN TECHNOLOGIES: SCALA, SPARK, HIVE, IMPALA, SQL, POSTGRESSQL, HBASE, HDFS, BASH, SSH, JENKINS, KAFKA

01/2020 - 10/2023

Big Data and Software Engineer

VT Solutions & Consulting

- · Consultant for a major German telecommunications company:
 - Data modeling and data partitioning in a Google Cloud Platform ecosystem.
 - Defining and developing DataFlow job using Scala for Ingestion and processing real-time and batch data.
 - Development of Airflow DAGs using Python to orchestrate ETL operations on data for a DWH.
 MAIN TECHNOLOGIES: SCALA, PYTHON, BIG QUERY, COMPOSER, SQL, POSTGRESSQL, BIG TABLE,
 GCS, BASH, JENKINS, KAFKA, PUB SUB, AIRFLOW, SONARQUBE
- Consultant for a major Italian telecommunications company. The main task was to write some guideline documents about the main approaches and best practices in a Big Data platform and its reference environment
 - Software component structure and code documentation.
 - Git integration Strategy (with particular focus on branching models like Git-Flow and GitHub-Flow, code and environment promotion).
 - Data Lake principles (data ingestion, data preparation, data exporting, testing).
 - Lambda architecture, data modeling, data preparation, partitioning.
 - Analysis for migration of Cloudera Ecosystem to Google Cloud Platform.
- · Consultant for a major Italian energy company.
 - Development of Apache Spark batch jobs using Scala for ingestion and processing of Avro file landed in HDFS.
 - Design and development of Data Quality Spark Processing Jobs for reports based on Hive and Impala.
 - Data Lake principles (data ingestion, data preparation, data exporting, testing).
 - Data preparation, data modelling and data partitioning.

MAIN TECHNOLOGIES: SCALA, JAVA, PYTHON, SQL, POSTGRESSQL, BASH, JENKINS, SONARQUBE

CERTIFICATIONS

7/2022 - 7/2024 GCP Professional Data Engineer

Google Cloud

certified link

O2/2022 Astronomer Certification for Apache Airflow Fundamentals and DAG Authoring

Astronomer

certified link Fundamentals certified link DAG Authoring

10/2023 PET B1 University of Cambridge

certified link

10/2019 Best Student Machine Learning Università della Calabria - Department of Mathematics and Computer Science

certified link

09/2012 - 10/2012 Attendance course at ETC International College

ETC International College, Bournemouth, England

certified link

EDUCATION —			
2021	Master Degree in Computer Science Università della Calabria - Department of Mathematics and Computer Science		University of Calabria
2017	Bachelor Degree in Computer Science Università della Calabria - Department of Mathematics and Computer Science		University of Calabria
LANGUAGES —		DRIVING LICENCE	
English - B1+, Italian - native		Driving Licence: A1, B	